<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Learning Analytics | Jihed Makhlouf</title><link>jihedmakhlouf.rf.gd/tag/learning-analytics/</link><atom:link href="jihedmakhlouf.rf.gd/tag/learning-analytics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Learning Analytics</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Jihed Makhlouf - 2022 | All opinions expressed here are my own and do not necessarily represent those of my employers or collaborators.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>jihedmakhlouf.rf.gd/media/picture.jpg</url><title>Learning Analytics</title><link>jihedmakhlouf.rf.gd/tag/learning-analytics/</link></image><item><title>Coursebot</title><link>jihedmakhlouf.rf.gd/project/coursebot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>jihedmakhlouf.rf.gd/project/coursebot/</guid><description>&lt;p>Based on the findings of the &lt;a href="jihedmakhlouf.rf.gd/project/comments/">&lt;em>Comments Data Mining&lt;/em>&lt;/a> project, we build an integrated platform to support both students and professors during the course. The students will engage in a discussion with a chatbot that will ask them questions related to some predefined aspects about their learning activities. The chatbot gives the appropriate feedback message to each student. Meanwhile, we gather the student textual data, process it, and use predictive models to generate reports for the professor.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>E-book Systems</title><link>jihedmakhlouf.rf.gd/project/e-book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>jihedmakhlouf.rf.gd/project/e-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>The BookRoll system is an online teaching material delivery system. It is an environment that allows students to have seamless access to the lecture contents, anytime, anywhere. On top of that, it provides additional functionalities that help the students interact with the documents. Moreover, the system gathers and stores students' usage data. Then, this data is used for various analyses. I used data from this system to investigate the students' reading behaviors and predict their scores.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Predicting Student Exam Scores Based on Click stream Level Data of Their Usage of an E Book System</title><link>jihedmakhlouf.rf.gd/publication/lak20_wk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>jihedmakhlouf.rf.gd/publication/lak20_wk/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Investigating Reading Behaviors within Student Reading Sessions to Predict their Performance</title><link>jihedmakhlouf.rf.gd/publication/lak19_wk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>jihedmakhlouf.rf.gd/publication/lak19_wk/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>