<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Jihed Makhlouf</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/</link><atom:link href="https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Jihed Makhlouf</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Jihed Makhlouf - 2022 | All opinions expressed here are my own and do not necessarily represent those of my employers or collaborators.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/media/picture.jpg</url><title>Jihed Makhlouf</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/</link></image><item><title>Achievements</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/achievements/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/achievements/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Comments Data Mining</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/comments/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/comments/</guid><description>&lt;p>Understanding students' behavior and learning experience is an important task in educational settings. In this project, students are asked to fill out a survey composed of questions related to their learning activities, after each lesson. The students' freely-written comments to each question are helpful to grasp their learning activity. But, the students have to wait a long time before receiving the professor&amp;rsquo;s feedback to their survey answers. Therefore, the aim of this project is twofold. First, we build prediction models of the students' learning experience based on their comments. Second, we automate the process of giving feedback to the students. Therefore, they don&amp;rsquo;t need to wait for a long time before receiving the appropriate guidance. This project later evolved into the &lt;a href="https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/coursebot/">&lt;em>CourseBot&lt;/em>&lt;/a> project.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Coursebot</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/coursebot/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/coursebot/</guid><description>&lt;p>Based on the findings of the &lt;a href="https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/comments/">&lt;em>Comments Data Mining&lt;/em>&lt;/a> project, we build an integrated platform to support both students and professors during the course. The students will engage in a discussion with a chatbot that will ask them questions related to some predefined aspects about their learning activities. The chatbot gives the appropriate feedback message to each student. Meanwhile, we gather the student textual data, process it, and use predictive models to generate reports for the professor.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>E-book Systems</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/e-book/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/e-book/</guid><description>&lt;p>The BookRoll system is an online teaching material delivery system. It is an environment that allows students to have seamless access to the lecture contents, anytime, anywhere. On top of that, it provides additional functionalities that help the students interact with the documents. Moreover, the system gathers and stores students' usage data. Then, this data is used for various analyses. I used data from this system to investigate the students' reading behaviors and predict their scores.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Experience</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/experience/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/experience/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Programming Web Search</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/trackthink/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/trackthink/</guid><description>&lt;p>When programmers face problems during programming tasks, they turn to the web to search for a solution. Similarly, students learning to program use the same tools to overcome their problems. Most of the researchers interested in tracking students' programming web search behavior merely store the URL of the visited websites. In this project, we went further by collecting almost all possible data from the students' usage of the web browser. For this, we build a browser extension (mainly Chromium-based browsers) called TrackThink to collect logs such as the tabs management, the page content and viewport, and the scrolling and clipboard usage. Such granular and specific data could not be collected otherwise as it requires advanced access only available through the browsers' extensions APIs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>STEM Career Prediction</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/stem/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/stem/</guid><description>&lt;p>STEM is an abbreviation of Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math. In recent years, there has been a constant increase in the demand for STEM-related workforce. Moreover, there is a large number of students that lose interest in STEM early or are not fully prepared to participate in these fields. In this context, the team behind the ASSISTments intelligent tutoring system conducted a longitudinal study that led to a data mining competition. Participants are requested to predict which students will pursue a STEM career using data from their interactions with the ASSISTments ITS. In this competition, I won second place and shared my findings in different papers submitted to the educational data mining conference and journal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>A Privacy-aware Browser Extension to Track User Search Behavior for Programming Course Supplement</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/mobiquitous21/</link><pubDate>Mon, 08 Nov 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/mobiquitous21/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Automatic Evaluation of Students' Learning Experience Based on Their Freely-Written Comments</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/springer_csedu21/</link><pubDate>Sat, 09 Oct 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/springer_csedu21/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Mining Students’ Comments to Build an Automated Feedback System</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/csedu21/</link><pubDate>Sun, 25 Apr 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/csedu21/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Automatic Feedback Models to Students Freely Written Comments</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/icce20/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Nov 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/icce20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Analysis of Click-Stream Data to Predict STEM Careers from Student Usage of an Intelligent Tutoring System</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/jedm20/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/jedm20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Prediction Models for Automatic Assessment to Students’ Freely-written Comments</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/csedu20/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/csedu20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Predicting Student Exam Scores Based on Click stream Level Data of Their Usage of an E Book System</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/lak20_wk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Mar 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/lak20_wk/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Investigating Reading Behaviors within Student Reading Sessions to Predict their Performance</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/lak19_wk/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/lak19_wk/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Investigating How School Aggregated Data Can Influence in Predicting STEM Career from Student usage of an Intelligent Tutoring System</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/edm18_wk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/edm18_wk/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Predicting if students will pursue a STEM career using School Aggregated Data from their usage of an Intelligent Tutoring System</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/edm18_poster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/edm18_poster/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>