<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Intelligent Tutoring System | Jihed Makhlouf</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/tag/intelligent-tutoring-system/</link><atom:link href="https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/tag/intelligent-tutoring-system/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Intelligent Tutoring System</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Jihed Makhlouf - 2022 | All opinions expressed here are my own and do not necessarily represent those of my employers or collaborators.</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/media/picture.jpg</url><title>Intelligent Tutoring System</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/tag/intelligent-tutoring-system/</link></image><item><title>STEM Career Prediction</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/stem/</link><pubDate>Sat, 15 Jan 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/project/stem/</guid><description>&lt;p>STEM is an abbreviation of Science, Technology, Engineering, and Math. In recent years, there has been a constant increase in the demand for STEM-related workforce. Moreover, there is a large number of students that lose interest in STEM early or are not fully prepared to participate in these fields. In this context, the team behind the ASSISTments intelligent tutoring system conducted a longitudinal study that led to a data mining competition. Participants are requested to predict which students will pursue a STEM career using data from their interactions with the ASSISTments ITS. In this competition, I won second place and shared my findings in different papers submitted to the educational data mining conference and journal.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Analysis of Click-Stream Data to Predict STEM Careers from Student Usage of an Intelligent Tutoring System</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/jedm20/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/jedm20/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Investigating How School Aggregated Data Can Influence in Predicting STEM Career from Student usage of an Intelligent Tutoring System</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/edm18_wk/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/edm18_wk/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Predicting if students will pursue a STEM career using School Aggregated Data from their usage of an Intelligent Tutoring System</title><link>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/edm18_poster/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 Jul 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://jihed-makhlouf.github.io/publication/edm18_poster/</guid><description/></item></channel></rss>